# Mohamed Abdalla **Frontend Developer**

# **Summary**

Talented and experienced front-end developer with 1+ years of experience executing with a plethora of diverse skills. Experience has taught me to take accessibility and responsiveness seriously, and I am excited to continue my career at Thrive Web Designs with a focus on making WordPress site developments easily accessible, completely responsive, and intuitive for users.

## **Education**

Master of Business Administration (Information Technology)

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Hyderabad, India / From 2017 to 2020

**Bachelor of computer Science(B.SC)** 

Osmania University Hyderabad, India / From 2013 to 2016

# Work experience

#### **Web Developer**

Jubna Dubai, United Arab Emirates / Since January 2022

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities:**

- Creating dashboard & static ads pages for company products.
- Fixing bugs in Clients' websites And our company websites.
- Manage and fix issues on the <u>alsaudi24</u> blog website.
- Helping Clients set up Company Ads on their websites.
- Developed a custom WordPress theme.
- Created WordPress plugins for Jubna.

#### WordPress Web Developer

TNC IT Solutions Dubai, United Arab Emirates / From April 2021 to December 2021

#### Key Qualifications & Responsibilities:

- Manage website development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Establish an interactive and dynamic website that guarantees high traffic page views, and maximum user experience, generating a 45% increase in the company's sales revenue.
- Implement and maintain content management systems (primarily WordPress) and some Custom Website, including installation, configuration, troubleshooting, and creation of custom SLS plugins and content types. Develop and deploy upgrade/migration plans for content management systems.
- Formulated and implemented improvements on cleanup database, performance and security.
- Helped in the creation of new website features to update sites for new SEO rules.
- Provide adequate training to 4 staff members in internal web functions, including steps on how to make minor updates/changes independently.



- % https://mgumaa.com
- 0504117398
- Driving licence
- math Date of birth 12/06/1994
- Dubai Internet City Dubai -UAE
- □ Sudanese

# **Computer skills**

#### Languages

- HTML5/ CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap
- Javascript
- MySql
- Python
- PHP

# Tools, Frameworks, and Libraries

- WordPress
- Django
- React.js
- Git and GitHub
- SEO
- AWS

#### Software

- Chrome Dev Tools
- Sublime Text & visual studio code

# **Skills**

- Teamwork
- Pressing Handling
- Punctuality
- Dedication and Commitment

# Work experience

#### **Web Developer**

Scientifi analytical tools Dubai, United Arab Emirates / From September 2020 to March 2021

#### Key Qualifications & Responsibilities:

- Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for 3 projects with 100% on time delivery.
- Designed and developed user-friendly interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views and user experience.
- Fixed bug in existing websites and implemented enhancement the significantly improved web functionality and speed.
- Design new features for existing websites.
- Proactively liaise with the design team and project manager to ensure efficient and timely delivery of significant projects

# **Projects**

- Project 1 : <u>coinquora.com</u> (Coinquora Blog News Inc).
- Project 2 : tncteams (TNC Company Website).
- Project 3 : <u>cryptonewsland</u> (Crypto Blog Media).
- Project 4 : realresearcher.com/media (Real Research Survey).
- Project 5 : green-ride.net (Green Road Inc).
- Project 6 : green-wall.net (Green Road Inc).
- Project 7 : <u>print-wall.net</u> (Green Road Inc).
- Project 8 : <u>inspection-detection.com</u> (SAT Inc).
- Project 9 : <u>thenewscrypto.com</u> (Freelancer).

# **Courses & Training**

#### Internship

Pixxel Arts Hyderabad, India / From June 2019 to December 2019

- Collaborate with designers to create clean interface and simple, intuitive interaction and experiences.
- Carry out quality assurance test to discover errors and optimize usability.

#### CS50: CS50's Introduction to Computer Science

Harvardx edX / 2019

#### The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy Online / 2020

#### **Web Designing**

Pixxel Arts Hyderabad, India / From June 2019 to 2020

#### **Beginner PHP and MySQL Tutorial**

Udemy Online / 2020

#### **Photoshop CC for Beginners**

Udemy Online / 2019

#### The Definitive Ethical Hacking

Udemy Online / 2016

## Languages

Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

**English** (Full Professional)